shawacademy.com 2019-06-06

# Privacy Policy | Shaw Academy

## Shaw Academy Website Privacy Statement

Shaw Academy is committed to protecting your privacy and takes its responsibility regarding the security of customer information very seriously. Our website Privacy Statement sets out what information we collect, how we collect it, what we do with it and how we protect this information. Any personal data is collected and processed in accordance with Irish and EU data protection laws.

## Collection of Personal Data

 **Information you provide to us** :In order to facilitate the provision of education, we collect personal details from you together with information we learn about you from your use of our website. These details may include (where applicable) your name, address, telephone number, e-mail and IP addresses, credit/debit card or other payment details, personal goals, account profile photos, ratings, webinar chat, or otherwise provide information to us through our services elsewhere.

 **Information we collect automatically** : We collect information about you and your use of our service, your interactions with us and our advertising, as well as information regarding your computer or other device used to access our service (such as smart TVs, gaming systems and mobile devices). This information includes:

  * your activity on the Shaw Academy service, such as course selections and attendance/watch history;
  * your interactions with our email, webinar chat, push and text messaging;
  * details of your interactions with Customer Service, such as the date, time and reason for contacting us, transcripts of any chat conversations, and if you call us, your phone number and call recordings;
  * device IDs or other unique identifiers;
  * advertising identifiers, such as those on mobile devices, tablets, and streaming media devices that include such identifiers (see the “Cookies and Internet Advertising” section below for more information);
  * device and software characteristics (such as type and configuration), connection information, statistics on page views, referring source (for example, referral URLs), IP address (which may tell us your general location), browser and standard web server log information;
  * information collected via the use of cookies, web beacons and other technologies, including ad data (such as information on the availability and delivery of ads, the site URL, as well as the date and time). (See our “Cookies and Internet Advertising” section for more details.)

To provide location-based services we may collect, use, and share precise location data, including the real-time geographic location of your computer or device through GPS, Bluetooth, and your IP address, along with crowd-sourced Wi-Fi hotspot and cell tower locations. This location data is collected anonymously, unless you provide consent. You may withdraw consent to Shaw Academy and our partners’ collection, use, transmission, processing and maintenance of location and account data at any time by not using the location-based features and turning off the Location Services settings (as applicable) on your device and computer.

## USE OF PERSONAL DATA

We use information to provide, analyze, administer, enhance and personalize our services and marketing efforts, to process your registration, your orders and your payments, and to communicate with you on these and other topics. For example, we use information to: provide products and services you request, contacting you regarding your course, credit or other payment card verification/screening, legal purposes, statistical and marketing analysis, systems testing, customer surveys, customer relations communications and offering you services and products we believe may interest you.

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Statement will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect and use it. We will normally collect personal information from you where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you (for example, to provide our services to you), where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms (for example, our direct marketing activities in accordance with your preferences), or where we have your consent to do so (for example, for you to participate in certain consumer insights activities like specific surveys and focus groups). In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person (for example, to prevent payment fraud or confirm your identity). For questions about our use of your personal information (including legal bases and transfer mechanisms we rely on), cookies or similar technologies, please contact our Data Protection Officer/Privacy Office by email at privacy@shawacademy.com.

## Sharing information about you

We follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of student information.

We may disclose your information to trusted contracted companies who act as “data processors” on our behalf for the purposes set out in this Privacy Statement. Shaw Academy has transfer agreements in place with all entities to which it transfers data for processing on its behalf. The agreements provide for specific and limited processing of user data in service of Shaw Academy’s operations and have been prepared so as to meet the requirements of Irish and EU law.

We may also pass your information on to government authorities or enforcement bodies for compliance with legal requirements.

Shaw Academy operates businesses in multiple jurisdictions, some of which are not located in the European Economic Area (EEA). While countries outside the EEA do not always have strong data protection laws, we will ensure that Shaw Academy and our services providers process your information in a secure manner and in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

You may be able to access third party social media services through our website or before coming to our website. When you are registered with your social service account, we will obtain the personal information you choose to share with us through these social media services pursuant to their privacy settings in order to improve and personalize your use of our website. This may include a list of friends and reviews of other users in your network. We may also use social media plugins on our website. As a result your information will be shared with your social media provider and possibly presented on your social media profile to be shared with others in your network. Please refer to the privacy policy of these third-party social media providers to find out more about these practices. 

## Shaw Academy Student/Members Area

All data collected upon registration in Shaw Academy will be processed in line with this Privacy Statement. In your personal Shaw Academy student area we store all your course information, so that you can access it whenever you wish.

We understand the importance of taking extra precautions to protect the privacy and safety of children. Accordingly, children under 16 will not be permitted to open a Shaw Academy account. We will take reasonable steps to delete any Shaw Academy account or information created by a child under 16, as soon as we learn about it.

All payment details are transmitted over a secure connection (Secure Socket Layer-SSL) across dedicated network infrastructure (Multiprotocol Label Switching-MPLS) and stored in compliance with Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards (PCI DSS).

You will have the option to stay signed-in into your Shaw Academy account by checking the “remember me” box. This option will only apply to the computer / device and the browser that you’re using when you select the box. If you do not wish to stay signed on a particular browser, simply sign out of your Shaw Academy account on that browser.

You may delete your Shaw Academy account by contacting Shaw Academy support [here](mailto:privacy@shawacademy.com) (Please see your Rights Section for more details).

## Direct Marketing Material

From time to time we or our selected partners may contact you with information regarding course promotions and ancillary products via email or SMS. However, you will be given the opportunity on every e-communication that we or our trusted partners send you to indicate that you no longer wish to receive our or their direct marketing material.

##YOUR CHOICES

 **Email and Text Messages** : If you no longer want to receive certain communications from us via email or text message, simply click the “unsubscribe” link in the email or reply STOP (or as otherwise instructed) to the text message. Please note that you cannot unsubscribe from service-related correspondence from us, such as messages relating to your student account transactions or course lesson reminders or information directly relating to your course progress.

 **Push Notifications** : You can choose to receive mobile push notifications from Shaw Academy. If you subsequently decide you no longer wish to receive these notifications, you can use your mobile device’s settings functionality to turn them off.

 **Interest-Based Ads** : Interest-based ads are online ads that are tailored to your likely interests based on your use of various apps and websites across the Internet. If you are using a browser, then cookies and web beacons can be used to collect information to help determine your likely interests. If you are using a mobile device, tablet, or streaming media device that includes an advertising identifier, then that identifier can be used to help determine your likely interests. For your choices about interest-based ads from Shaw Academy, please see the “Cookies” section (below).

## Site tracking

We use tracking software to monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help us develop the design and layout of the websites. This software does not enable us to capture any personal passenger information.

## Cookies

This site uses cookies to enable us to improve our service to you and to provide certain features that you may find useful (click here for Shaw Academy’s Cookie Policy).

We and our Service Providers use cookies and other technologies (such as web beacons), as well as advertising identifiers, for various reasons. For example, we use these technologies to make it easy to access our services by remembering you when you return, to provide and analyze our services. We also use cookies, as well as advertising identifiers, to learn more about our users and their likely interests, and to deliver and tailor marketing or advertising. We want you to be informed about our use of these technologies, so this section explains the types of technologies we use, what they do and your choices regarding their use.

 **What are cookies?** Cookies are small text files that are transferred to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser to enable us to recognise your browser and help us to track visitors to our site; thus enabling us to understand better the products and services that will be most suitable to you. A cookie contains your contact information and information to allow us to identify your computer when you travel around our site for the purpose of helping you accomplish your registration. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but, if you wish, you can set your browser to prevent it from accepting cookies. The “help” portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. The cookies we use do not detect any information stored on your computers.

You can opt-out of third-party personalised advertising cookies, please review our cookie policy for more information.

For more information about cookies and how to stop cookies being installed visit the following website: [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

## Links to Third Party Websites

This privacy statement only covers websites that we own and control. It does not cover links to other websites and accordingly any information collected by those parties that own and control those websites or their use of cookies set from their domains when you visit their websites. Please be aware that individual third-party organizations operate their own policies regarding the use and sale of personal information and the use of cookies. If you have a concern regarding the way your personal information will be used on other sites or on the type of cookies used and how they are being used then you are advised to read the relevant privacy statement and cookie policy or in the absence of such a statement and policy on the site, contact the company concerned. Any data stored by third party websites are stored completely separately by third party.

## Security

We take great care to ensure the security of our website. The data you provide to us is protected using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology. SSL is the industry standard method of encrypting personal information and credit card details so that they can be securely transferred over the Internet.

## Your Rights

You can request access to your personal information or correct or update out-of-date or inaccurate personal information we hold about you.

You can most easily do this by visiting the “account” section within your Members Area, where you have the ability to access and update your contact information. You must be signed in to access the “account” section. You may also request that we delete personal information that we hold about you.

To make requests, or if you have any other question regarding our privacy practices, please contact our data protection officer/privacy office at privacy@shawacademy.com. We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws. Please also see the “your choices” section of this privacy statement for additional choices regarding your information.

You can object to processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information; if we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time; withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent; you have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information by contacting us here.

We may retain information as required or permitted by applicable laws and regulations, including to honor your choices, for our billing or records purposes and to fulfill the purposes described in this privacy statement. We take reasonable measures to destroy or de-identify personal information in a secure manner when it is no longer required.

## Our registered address is:

Shaw Academy  
26 Fitzwilliam Street Upper,  
Grand Canal Dock, Dublin 2,  
D02 CT89, Ireland

## Changes to Privacy Statement

Our Privacy Statement may change from time to time and any changes to the statement will be posted on this page.
